<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Bin Wang&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working from Home during the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 22:11:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a post that i will be writing and updating during the coming weeks while working from home all because of the coronavirus pandemic, as a personal record while getting through this global chaos.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening preceding working from home becasue of UCI asking all to minimize campus presence, after setting up the work station an idea suddently poped up in my head: why not writing a blog about this speccial period? The reasons to do this are obvious, which renders the motivation strong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First of all, the fundamental reason leading to this decision is totally becasue of the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second,I am confident to say i never worked from home (never is not the correct word choice, especially as a scientist). By never, i mean i have never worked from home fromally since the 2nd year of my PhD back in 2015, but only briefly, e.g., reading a paper on my phone and fixing my Github-hosted website very recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these two reasons, I am thinking it would be interesing to record this period of working from home to offer my personal experience about this special phase of a pandemic in human history. And this idea accidentally echos what a UVa professor is trying to let his/her students do during this pandemic&amp;ndash;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.virginia.edu/content/write-it-down-historian-suggests-keeping-record-life-during-pandemic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Write it Down&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-march-16th-2020-a-day-of-loss&#34;&gt;Day 1: March 16th, 2020 (A day of loss)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a productive day! In the morning tried to work on microbial drought legacy project with respect to data analysis, but did not go well. In the afternoon tried best to figure out a specific analysis needed to be done for a long term, and had a meeting with postdoc advisor. Working from home the 1st day was not as productive as usual in office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite interesting to see during my two breaks from working how things are changing because of the virus. At noon, found a person designated holding the door for customers in a restaurant. In the evening, headed out to a grocery store, and everything was gone, especially the frozen food, which i eat a lot usually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2-march-17th-2020-the-day-started-from-noon&#34;&gt;Day 2: March 17th, 2020 (The day started from noon)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up pretty late around 10:30. Before a take-out lunch, i only worked only about 1 hour. Being afraid of virus transmission, i finished my lunch in a nearby park, where people were scarce. Tried hard to really work on my project, in the afternoon i found the good feeling of working usually in office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the situation of coronavirus is getting worse and worse. State and local level strategies are increasingly aggresive. I really started to worry about or feel a little afraid of the risk of getting infected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sitation is evoving very fast. Stay Alert.





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/gizmo_hu91f4089620be43da0894418111ab5f39_555914_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cat Gizmo of my house owner is on alert&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/gizmo_hu91f4089620be43da0894418111ab5f39_555914_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1575&#34; height=&#34;2100&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cat Gizmo of my house owner is on alert
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-march-18th-2020-air-full-of-virus&#34;&gt;Day 3: March 18th, 2020 (Air full of virus)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are changing very fast since yesterday. Locally, people and cars were much less and were even rarely been seen than yesterday in restaruants and parking lots. Globally, the cases continue to climb up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mid-afternoon I went to a park after grabbinga coffe to get some fresh air. Though the spring is comming, but i feel the atmosphere is filled with virus, and we are immersed in the virus. What we inhale is just virus. What a feeling!





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/park_hu48927ce7e149c446b5b7938fc6a96098_361516_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;View of soccer field in the Arroyo Park&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/park_hu48927ce7e149c446b5b7938fc6a96098_361516_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;937&#34; height=&#34;1665&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    View of soccer field in the Arroyo Park
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-4march-19th-2020-here-comes-the-spring&#34;&gt;Day 4(March 19th, 2020): Here comes the spring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With intermittent rain all day, spring finally comes to Southern California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A day without any speciality personally. However,the cases confirmed and death toll are soaring. The state of california is projected to have more than a half of its 30 million people would contract the virus(
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kcra.com/article/newsom-more-than-half-of-california-projected-to-contract-covid-19/31791343&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;), which is really alarming. In the afternoon, I drunk wine with my roommate and had a good conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo of the pacific ocean near Newport Coast while i went to grocery store for some frozen food.





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/pacific_ocean_hu900d1201e3bdc1ccb91d69b1b0266f0f_1282823_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;View of Pacific Oeacn across the Pacific Highway(PCH) at Crystal Cove State Park&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/pacific_ocean_hu900d1201e3bdc1ccb91d69b1b0266f0f_1282823_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;3024&#34; height=&#34;4032&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    View of Pacific Oeacn across the Pacific Highway(PCH) at Crystal Cove State Park
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-5march-20th-2020-warning-against-over-optimism&#34;&gt;Day 5(March 20th, 2020): Warning against over-optimism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With five days into working from home, I have adjusted to working by my bed. And it&amp;rsquo;s the first day that i did not head out besides tossing garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locally, cases are increasing in Orange County. At the state level, California has issued a directive of asking people to shelter in palce. Here is a drone view of the streets in downtown Los Angeles. What an unbelievable scene!

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O51LOuQzROI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-6march-21st-2020-first-weekend-since-isolation&#34;&gt;Day 6(March 21st, 2020): First weekend since isolation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started the day receiving the news that UCI had the 1st confirmed case. Stayed at home for the whole day, working on projects and reading papers and witnessing the number of confirmed cases in US soaring. Nothing quite interesting to mention, but a post that i accidentally came across on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/defunkt/6443&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt; written by Chris Wanstrath, a co-creator of GitHub, is quite inspiring, though themed in computer science, programming, etc.for doing research regardless of field in terms of side project and open science. Here I list a few excerpts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why having side projects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“You should always have a side project, too. Side projects give you an outlet, provide a useful distraction, let you explore new ideas, learn new concepts, and generally give you the freedom to be unaccountable. You don’t have to worry about your boss, or your coworkers, or the damn commentators on Reddit. Just have some fun. Treat yourself.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why open source?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Open source can make wonderful things happen for you, and not just financially but socially too.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a open-source side project?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, start a side project. Who knows where it will take you.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-7march-22nd-2020history-of-science&#34;&gt;Day 7(March 22nd, 2020):History of science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to a grocery store to replenish my forozen food stock. suprised to see the store has started controlling the flow of shoppers since my last visit 3 days ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read some materials on history of science and the differences in development phase between physics and ecology. An article terms the combinatiion of ecology and physics ecophysics, arguing that relatively much more mature physics in terms of quantitatively addressing system complexity and emergence can inform the studies of ecology with respect to as many questions as biogeography, macroecology, biodiversity, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week working from home is leaving me with rain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-8march-23rd-2020-two-viruses&#34;&gt;Day 8(March 23rd, 2020): Two viruses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump said the administration should be able to do two things simultaneously in the Corornavirs Task Force News Briefing: contain the virus and open the country. He further explained that a lock-down of the whole country for a long period of time becasue of the virus will create other problems which can be even worse than the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing two viruses as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surving in the academia is not easy, which in fact is becoming increasingly hard for me. For objective reasons, the virus is affecting activies revolving around research, which dooms the job hunting. This is all the more so for me as a non-native speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both viruses are hard to defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-9march-24th-2020-get-it-done&#34;&gt;Day 9(March 24th, 2020): Get it done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying at home the whole day, working on my project and reading papers on machine learning. Uncertainties are looming not only for the virus but also for my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second week into isolation I started worrying more and more about my next stop. Doing another postdoc is going to be a sure thing. Where and when for this 2nd postdoc position are big questions I need to figure out soon. But one thing at this moment is absolutey right to do&amp;ndash;get the project done as soon as possilbe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-10march-25th-2020-the-worst-frozen-food&#34;&gt;Day 10(March 25th, 2020): The worst frozen food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 10 days in isolation from home, and I have been eating frozone food from Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s without a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Today&amp;rsquo;s lunch i had the worst frozen food, which sort of makes me desire to have some real food(though i am not a picky person for food). This cannot stay much longer. I suddently have an idea to order some ramen noodles from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monotone food is becoming a concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-11march-26th-2020-number-one&#34;&gt;Day 11(March 26th, 2020): Number one&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today US overtook China as the number one country of having the most confirmed coronavirus cases across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peak is coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headed out to grocery store and refill my frozen food after three days being not stepping outside of home. The feeling is increasingly complex.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ay6MLO2pd30&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-12march-27th-2020-grim-news&#34;&gt;Day 12(March 27th, 2020): Grim news&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A grim future is looming with the number of cases continuously soaring since yesterday when US became the top country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the virus spreads across the world and cases locally in Orange County keep climbing, worries are building up. These include among others the uncertainty of career and being afriad of sickness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-13march-28th-2020cookies&#34;&gt;Day 13(March 28th, 2020):Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on day toward the goal of finishing the 1st draft of my drought legacy manuscirpt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookies, as shown in the picture, and coffe my roomate generously offered really powered me up.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;



  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/cookie_huf1dcdc1a8f68df6c1a3dc4372d2132cf_412310_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;494&#34; height=&#34;494&#34;&gt;



  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cookies my roommate(landlord) made
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-14march-29th-2020-another-four-after-two-weeks&#34;&gt;Day 14(March 29th, 2020): Another four after two weeks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay in home until the end of April. This is new guidance from White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headed to grocery store to stock up some frozen food. I can clearly see the increasingly strict measures taken over th past two weeks. Along the pacific coast all parks were closed to vehicular access. Much less cars on roads and I do not know what is increasing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is still flying. Two weeks have past, and four more weeks are coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hNorM4Pwi0A&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-15march-30th-2020-nothing-to-say&#34;&gt;Day 15(March 30th, 2020): Nothing to say&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tried to start a side project on modelling forest structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-16march-31st-2020-hamiltonian-systems&#34;&gt;Day 16(March 31st, 2020): Hamiltonian systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are analogues of Hamiltonian systems of physics out there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to limit my out-of-door time to once a week. The situation in the coming two weeks is grim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-17april-1st2020-geometry&#34;&gt;Day 17(April 1st,2020): Geometry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Came across a very nice post on 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://intellectualmathematics.com/blog/societal-role-of-geometry-in-early-civilisations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the history of geometry&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;In ancient Mesopotamia and Egypt, mathematics meant law and order. Specialised mathematical technocrats were deployed to settle conflicts regarding taxes, trade contracts, and inheritance. Mathematics enabled states to develop civil branches of government instead of relying on force and violence. Mathematics enabled complex economies in which people could count on technically competent administration and an objective justice system.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did geometry start? Who was doing it, and why, in early civilisations? The Greeks invented theorem and proof, but long before them there was geometry in Egypt and Mesopotamia. So that’s practical geometry, applied geometry.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-18april-2nd-2020-how-natural-is-natural&#34;&gt;Day 18(April 2nd, 2020): How natural is natural?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;How natural is natural?&#39;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the title of the last chapter of the book by Loren Eiseley &lt;strong&gt;The Firmament of Time&lt;/strong&gt;, which aroused my strong interest to ask myself the same question. How natural is natural?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-19-april-3rd-2020-godwins-law&#34;&gt;Day 19 (April 3rd, 2020): Godwin&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Godwin&amp;rsquo;s law, i.e. the empirical observation that as an online discussion grows in time, the probability of a comparison with Nazis or Hitler quickly approaches unity, is one of the best-documented facts of the internet.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a paper that came out on April 1st, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13715&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quantum Godwin&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt;, quantum Gowin&amp;rsquo;s effect is proposed and numerically substantiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; the quantum Godwin effect is not only robust against noise, but actually enhanced by decoherence. We have as yet no theoretical explanation, nor a good application, for this astonishing behaviour, which we dub quantum hyperpiesia&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Website Hosted on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/create-github-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 22:23:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/create-github-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about creating a blog to write about my research and others for a long time. And i am actually having one using a free service provided by WordPress(
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bwangecology.wordpress.com/2018/11/24/documentary-of/amp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;) and another one using Google Blogger created when i was a PhD student.Many more providers of personal website and/or blog site are out there, e.g., WIX, Google Site, etc. And WordPress is actually one of the most popular ones among people of many industries. However, I always do not feel comfortable with these platforms, especially considering they are always not free if you want to get rid of annoying advertisments on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My attention was eventually drawn to GitHub. As one of the most popular code sharing platforms nowadays, it can also host websites as diverse as personal, group, projct, etc by storing source code, files, and other data. One clear advantage of using GitHub is it has NO ADs, offering us a clean persoanl website. So I did a little research on creating a blog on GitHub, and found the learning curve is not steep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is served as a brief tutorial for building a personal website hosted on Github using Hugo and the Academic theme. Many website builders analogous to Hugo are out there(e.g. Jekyll). Here i chose Hugo because of the popularity in academia of the Academic Theme built for it. Following the 3 steps below closely, you will be able to start your own GitHub website in a few minutes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-install-essential-softwares&#34;&gt;Step 1: Install essential softwares&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; installed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up a GitHub account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get either 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; or GitHub installed on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-create-github-repos&#34;&gt;Step 2: Create GitHub Repos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly create two git repositories both remotely under your GitHub account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fork the Academic Kickstart repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a repository named &amp;lsquo;yourname.github.io&amp;rsquo; (replace yourname with your own actual GitHub account name)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then clone these two repos to your computer locally. To do so, first open a terminal and then type the following shell command to install the Academic Theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/bioatmosphere/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-deploy-on-github&#34;&gt;Step 3: Deploy on GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, deploying a webiste on GitHub is powered by its feature, GitHub Page. Here is an example of using GitHub Page to display the microbial model I am working on: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/DEMENTpy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DEMENTpy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, run commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cd config/_default/
vi config.toml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the config.toml file, set baseurl = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://USERNAME.github.io/%22&#34;&gt;https://USERNAME.github.io/&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; (replace USERNAME with your own GitHub username).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now run a command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;git submodule add -f -b master https://github.com/USERNAME/USERNAME.github.io.git public
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add your USERNAME.github.io repository into a submodule in a folder named public, replacing with your Github username:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;hugo
cd public
git add .
git commit -m &amp;quot;Build website&amp;quot;
git push origin master
cd ..
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then what you need to do is just tailoring this site design framework futher to your own needs and flavor and creating contents spanning from blogs, slides, and pages to photos and videos. For all these refer to the Hugo and Academic Theme Documentation. For example, to write a new blog, run command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;hugo new --kind post post/my-first-post
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From IBM to ABM</title>
      <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/ibm-abm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 18:53:16 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/ibm-abm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My paper entitled “Soil aggregates as biogeochemical reactors and implications for soil-atmosphere exchange of greenhouse gases: a concept ” was eventually accepted by Global Change Biology at the onset of November, 2018 [1].  It is really not easy to get this good outcome. So, I just want to write this post as a documentary of the production of this paper, telling some stories ‘behind the paper’. In detail, first of all, i would articulate the central idea of this paper and its broad implications (if it has, hopefully) in a fairly broad context. Then, i am going to tell the origin of the idea and impetus in writing such a paper. Next, the journal submission process is literally described. Finally, i would love to share some of the lessons learned from completing this piece. Hopefully, these fairly personal lessons would inspire some of the readers of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-should-we-view-soil-systems&#34;&gt;HOW SHOULD WE VIEW SOIL SYSTEMS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soils to everyone are not a stranger. We are standing on them all the time only except the stage when we reach the end of our longevity. However, this is true to only individuals, which for the whole human population is forever true.  Presumably just because of this natural advantage generously offered by God we always ignore soils beneath our feet, simply and arrogantly thinking them as dirts. And even if in recent years we have started to appreciate its grand importance to the whole Earth System from as many sectors as science, society, environment, climate change, sustainability, etc., we still do not get one fundamental question answered—-How should we view soil systems beneath our feet methodologically? What’s the correct attitude should we hold toward soils?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to the traditional up-down approach, in this paper i contend that instead we should view soils from the bottom up. This idea is rooted in my dissertation research on individual-based modelling of forest ecosystems that has been ongoing since 1970s and pioneered by Botkin and Herman. Shugart (my advisor)[2].  In fact, this bottom-up methodology is broadly true in many other systems across the natural and societal systems [3]. For example, the recent special issue in Nature, ‘Bottom-up Biology[4]’,  echos this idea in soils systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fig.1 Schematic of Soil systems with aggregates being treated as the basic structural units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-was-the--idea-conceived-and-developed&#34;&gt;HOW WAS THE  IDEA CONCEIVED AND DEVELOPED?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially came up with this idea back in the Fall of  2013 when i was a freshly new PhD student in Department of Environmental Sciences, University of Virginia, located at the most beautiful college town in US, Charlottesville (as least so far i strongly hold up this opinion since i’ve been a few places in US though, of course, not all).  The background and specific reasons leading to the development of this idea are summarized as follows: 1) I did a project about non-microbial methane production from soils for my master thesis, which involved soil aggregation and aggregate-derived methane; This was the first time i approach this concept, which later i found really important in soil science. 2)  then I relatively had more time then and wanted to publish some papers beyond my doctoral dissertation research; 3) Google scholar has a function sending out the latest research related to my soil aggregate methane [5] research in the format of ‘Google Scholar Alert’. I found a couple of papers studying aggregate level GHG production during that period. Under these conditions, I made a decision to conduct a synthesis study of these published studies to write a review paper. The boring, frustrating, and time-consuming processes thus got started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;process-of-submission-to-journals&#34;&gt;PROCESS OF SUBMISSION TO JOURNALS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it’s really a tedious process even before its submission to Global Change Biology that got a good outcome eventually. Preceding this final submission, i’ve submitted it to four different soil-related journals (including GCB. Yes, submitted to it last year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1st submission (SBB; December 2014):  I first determined to submit this ms to SBB, which very fortunately was sent out for a peer-review promptly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2nd submission (SOIL 2015): This submission had not been sent out for peer review, but it was handled by Six. Everyone doing soil science, in particular soil aggregation research, should know him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3rd submission (GCB 2016): A very smooth submission experience with a fairly efficient peer review process. Unfortunately, it was rejected again, but with very good comments from two reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4th submission (GCB 2018): Since it was rejected in 2016, i have spent some time in further revising it , but most of my attention was directed to the my dissertation-related work. So it was not submitted again until early 2018 when i moved across US to UC, Irvine.  Finally accepted but with a fairly slow peer review process with two rounds of reject and resubmission preceding a direct acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;LESSONS LEARNED&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One primary lesson i learned throughout this process is that DON’T BE SHORT-SIGHTED. Never try to finish sth, especially a synthesis or a review paper quickly without a complete grasp of the big picture and details of the project. No one can do it,  especially for a brand-new idea that is being nurtured. It’s fairly normal to spend a lot of time working on it again and again (even for a senior scientist, i guess). Here are some specific suggestions i would give (lessons i learned):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be persistent&lt;/strong&gt; Do not give up early.  First of all, this is the thing that superimposes upon everything that i am going to list and articulate below.  This ‘never give up’ includes finishing the writing itself and journal submission. As regards journal submission,  if rejected with comments, do be humbly take up those comments (may really harsh) and try to revise the manuscript by incorporating these comments. And the writing is probably intertwined with the submission-rejection cycle. So keep working on it, and do not give it up once you have started this project. You will eventually get there( i mean the email saying ‘it’s a pleasure to notify you that you paper gets accepted…something like this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep thinking&lt;/strong&gt; No rush to get it done ASAP. Ideas or nice points would/will pop up during this process. What you need to do is to keep thinking about it. And do not forget about it, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep improving&lt;/strong&gt; This somewhat overlaps the second one,’ keep thinking’. We can’t have all ideas/points that should be included come up all at once. Some of them probably will only occur occasionally when, for example, you lie on the bed and reluctant to get up, have dinner, or something else (e.g., sitting on the toilet). When we have these ideas, we can record them and put them in the manuscript. Through this process, we continuously improve the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep trying&lt;/strong&gt; Journals nowadays are overwhelmingly rich in terms of journal names, publisher and publication mode. When you feel ready, submission to some journals would not be bad, as a submission with a peer-review would reap some either nice or bad comments, which, i think, will be all helpful for improving your manuscripts. And rejections from journals are totally fine, as you will have ample options of outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang, Bin, Paul E. Brewer, Herman H. Shugart, Manuel T. Lerdau, and Steven D. Allison. “Soil aggregates as biogeochemical reactors and implications for soil‐atmosphere exchange of greenhouse gases—a concept.” Global change biology (2018). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.14515&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.14515&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shugart, H. H. (1984). A theory of forest dynamics. The ecological implications of forest succession models. Springer-Verlag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West, G. (2017). Scale: the universal laws of growth, innovation, sustainability, and the pace of life in organisms, cities, economies, and companies. Penguin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendal Powell How biologists are creating life-like cells from scratch &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/collections/bsmxgstsgy&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/collections/bsmxgstsgy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang, B., Hou, L., Liu, W., &amp;amp; Wang, Z. (2013). Non-microbial methane emissions from soils. Atmospheric environment, 80, 290-298. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2013.08.010&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2013.08.010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
