<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>record | Bin Wang&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/tags/record/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bioatmosphere.github.io/tags/record/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>record</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 22:11:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>record</title>
      <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/tags/record/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working from Home during the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 22:11:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This will be a post that i will be writing and updating during the coming weeks while working from home all because of the coronavirus pandemic, as a personal record of this global chaos.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening preceding working from home becasue of UCI asking all to minimize campus presence, after setting up the work station an idea sudently poped up in my head: why not writing a blog about this speccial period? The reasons to do this are obvious, which renders the motivation strong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First of all, the fundamental reason leading to this decision is totally becasue of the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second,I am confident to say i never worked from home (never is not the correct word choice, especially as a scientist). By never, i mean i have never worked from home fromally since the 2nd year of my PhD back in 2015, but only briefly, e.g., reading a paper on my phone and fixing my Github-hosted website very recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these two reasons, I am thinking it would be interesing to record this period of working from home and offer my personal experience about this special phase of a pandemic in human history. And this idea accidentally echos what a UVa professor is trying to let his/her students do during this pandemic&amp;ndash;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.virginia.edu/content/write-it-down-historian-suggests-keeping-record-life-during-pandemic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Write it Down&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-march-16th-2020-a-day-of-loss&#34;&gt;Day 1: March 16th, 2020 (A day of loss)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a productive day! In the morning tried to work on microbial drought legacy project with respect to data analysis, but did not go well. In the afternoon tried best to figure out a specific analysis needed to be done for a long term, and had a meeting with postdoc advisor. Working from home the 1st day was not as productive as usual in office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite interesting to see during my two breaks from working how things are changing because of the virus. At noon, found a person designated holding the door for customers in a restaurant. In the evening, headed out to a grocery store, and everything was gone, especially the frozen food, which i eat a lot usually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2-march-17th-2020-the-day-started-from-noon&#34;&gt;Day 2: March 17th, 2020 (The day started from noon)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up pretty late around 10:30. Before a take-out lunch, i only worked only about 1 hour. Being afraid of virus transmission, i finished my lunch in a nearby park, where people were scarce. Tried hard to really work on my project, in the afternoon i found the good feeling of working usually in office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the situation of coronavirus is getting worse and worse. State and local level strategies are increasingly aggresive. I really started to worry about or feel a little afraid of the risk of getting infected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sitation is evoving very fast. Stay Alert.





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/gizmo_hu91f4089620be43da0894418111ab5f39_555914_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cat Gizmo of my house owner is on alert&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/gizmo_hu91f4089620be43da0894418111ab5f39_555914_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1575&#34; height=&#34;2100&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cat Gizmo of my house owner is on alert
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-march-18th-2020-air-full-of-virus&#34;&gt;Day 3: March 18th, 2020 (Air full of virus)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are changing very fast since yesterday. Locally, people and cars were much less and were even rarely been seen than yesterday in restaruants and parking lots. Globally, the cases continue to climb up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mid-afternoon I went to a park after grabbinga coffe to get some fresh air. Though the spring is comming, but i feel the atmosphere is filled with virus, and we are immersed in the virus. What we inhale is just virus. What a feeling!





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/park_hu48927ce7e149c446b5b7938fc6a96098_361516_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;View of soccer field in the Arroyo Park&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/park_hu48927ce7e149c446b5b7938fc6a96098_361516_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;937&#34; height=&#34;1665&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    View of soccer field in the Arroyo Park
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-4march-19th-2020-here-comes-the-spring&#34;&gt;Day 4(March 19th, 2020): Here comes the spring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With intermittent rain all day, spring finally comes to Southern California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A day without any speciality personally. However,the cases confirmed and death toll are soaring. The state of california is projected to have more than a half of its 30 million people would contract the virus(
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kcra.com/article/newsom-more-than-half-of-california-projected-to-contract-covid-19/31791343&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;), which is really alarming. In the afternoon, I drunk wine with my roommate and had a good conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo of the pacific ocean near Newport Coast while i went to grocery store for some frozen food.





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/pacific_ocean_hu900d1201e3bdc1ccb91d69b1b0266f0f_1282823_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;View of Pacific Oeacn across the Pacific Highway(PCH) at Crystal Cove State Park&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/pacific_ocean_hu900d1201e3bdc1ccb91d69b1b0266f0f_1282823_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;3024&#34; height=&#34;4032&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    View of Pacific Oeacn across the Pacific Highway(PCH) at Crystal Cove State Park
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-5march-20th-2020-warning-against-over-optimism&#34;&gt;Day 5(March 20th, 2020): Warning against over-optimism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With five days into working from home, I have adjusted to working by my bed. And it&amp;rsquo;s the first day that i did not head out besides tossing garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locally, cases are increasing in Orange County. At the state level, California has issued a directive of asking people to shelter in palce. Here is a drone view of the streets in downtown Los Angeles. What an unbelievable scene!

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O51LOuQzROI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-6march-21st-2020-first-weekend-since-isolation&#34;&gt;Day 6(March 21st, 2020): First weekend since isolation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started the day receiving the news that UCI had the 1st confirmed case. Stayed at home for the whole day, working on projects and reading papers and witnessing the number of confirmed cases in US soaring. Nothing quite interesting to mention, but a post that i accidentally came across on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/defunkt/6443&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt; written by Chris Wanstrath, a co-creator of GitHub, is quite inspiring, though themed in computer science, programming, etc.for doing research regardless of field in terms of side project and open science. Here I list a few excerpts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why having side projects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“You should always have a side project, too. Side projects give you an outlet, provide a useful distraction, let you explore new ideas, learn new concepts, and generally give you the freedom to be unaccountable. You don’t have to worry about your boss, or your coworkers, or the damn commentators on Reddit. Just have some fun. Treat yourself.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why open source?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Open source can make wonderful things happen for you, and not just financially but socially too.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a open-source side project?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, start a side project. Who knows where it will take you.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-7march-22nd-2020history-of-science&#34;&gt;Day 7(March 22nd, 2020):History of science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to a grocery store to replenish my forozen food stock. suprised to see the store has started controlling the flow of shoppers since my last visit 3 days ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read some materials on history of science and the differences in development phase between physics and ecology. An article terms the combinatiion of ecology and physics ecophysics, arguing that relatively much more mature physics in terms of quantitatively addressing system complexity and emergence can inform the studies of ecology with respect to as many questions as biogeography, macroecology, biodiversity, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week working from home is leaving me with rain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-8march-23rd-2020-two-viruses&#34;&gt;Day 8(March 23rd, 2020): Two viruses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump said the administration should be able to do two things simultaneously in the Corornavirs Task Force News Briefing: contain the virus and open the country. He further explained that a lock-down of the whole country for a long period of time becasue of the virus will create other problems which can be even worse than the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing two viruses as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surving in the academia is not easy, which in fact is becoming increasingly hard for me. For objective reasons, the virus is affecting activies revolving around research, which dooms the job hunting. This is all the more so for me as a non-native speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both viruses are hard to defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-9march-24th-2020-get-it-done&#34;&gt;Day 9(March 24th, 2020): Get it done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying at home the whole day, working on my project and reading papers on machine learning. Uncertainties are looming not only for the virus but also for my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second week into isolation I started worrying more and more about my next stop. Doing another postdoc is going to be a sure thing. Where and when for this 2nd postdoc position are big questions I need to figure out soon. But one thing at this moment is absolutey right to do&amp;ndash;get the project done as soon as possilbe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-10march-25th-2020-the-worst-frozen-food&#34;&gt;Day 10(March 25th, 2020): The worst frozen food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 10 days in isolation from home, and I have been eating frozone food from Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s without a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Today&amp;rsquo;s lunch i had the worst frozen food, which sort of makes me desire to have some real food(though i am not a picky person for food). This cannot stay much longer. I suddently have an idea to order some ramen noodles from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monotone food is becoming a concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-11march-26th-2020-number-one&#34;&gt;Day 11(March 26th, 2020): Number one&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today US overtook China as the number one country of having the most confirmed coronavirus cases across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peak is coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headed out to grocery store and refill my frozen food after three days being not stepping outside of home. The feeling is increasingly complex.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ay6MLO2pd30&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-12march-27th-2020-grim-news&#34;&gt;Day 12(March 27th, 2020): Grim news&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A grim future is looming with the number of cases continuously soaring since yesterday when US became the top country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the virus spreads across the world and cases locally in Orange County keep climbing, worries are building up. These include among others the uncertainty of career and being afriad of sickness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-13march-28th-2020cookies&#34;&gt;Day 13(March 28th, 2020):Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on day toward the goal of finishing the 1st draft of my drought legacy manuscirpt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookies, as shown in the picture, and coffe my roomate generously offered really powered me up.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure&gt;



  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://bioatmosphere.github.io/post/work-from-home-coronavirus/cookie_huf1dcdc1a8f68df6c1a3dc4372d2132cf_412310_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;494&#34; height=&#34;494&#34;&gt;



  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cookies my roommate(landlord) made
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-14march-29th-2020-another-four-after-two-weeks&#34;&gt;Day 14(March 29th, 2020): Another four after two weeks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay in home until the end of April. This is new guidance from White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headed to grocery store to stock up some frozen food. I can clearly see the increasingly strict measures taken over th past two weeks. Along the pacific coast all parks were closed to vehicular access. Much less cars on roads and I do not know what is increasing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is still flying. Two weeks have past, and four more weeks are coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hNorM4Pwi0A&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-15march-30th-2020-nothing-to-say&#34;&gt;Day 15(March 30th, 2020): Nothing to say&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tried to start a side project on modelling forest structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-16march-31st-2020-hamiltonian-systems&#34;&gt;Day 16(March 31st, 2020): Hamiltonian systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are analogues of Hamiltonian systems of physics out there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to limit my out-of-door time to once a week. The situation in the coming two weeks is grim.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
